<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Vigilante&#39;s Pride</title>
    <link>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Vigilante&#39;s Pride</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <atom:link href="http://aviral19.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-am-aviral-bajpai-pursuing-mechanical-engineering-and-masters-in-biology-from-bits-pilani-goa-campus:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;I am Aviral Bajpai, pursuing Mechanical engineering and Masters in Biology from BITS Pilani, Goa Campus.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am an enthusiast learner. In fact I just learned hugo to develop this site.
I am interested in Machine learning and Artificial intelligence, although I am developing a new interest in Biology and maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll find something interesting in Mechanical as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;somethime-about-me:6083a88ee3411b0d17ce02d738f69d47&#34;&gt;Somethime about me:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am an introvert, I can talk to hundreds of people online, but I stay quite when in group, I don&amp;rsquo;t usually introduce myself and would prefer reading books in my room than visiting beaches in Goa.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am a night owl, I usually wake up till 2 in the morning and sometimes might not sleep the entire night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am an avid reader. Yes, I love reading and I read a lot, usually non fiction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am an engineer and hence Single.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most importantly&lt;/strong&gt; I am an enthusiastic learner. I would try to learn anything new I come across, if that seems interesting to me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happy Birthday Pandey</title>
      <link>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/post/happybday/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jul 2017 00:00:48 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/post/happybday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when you are afraid to post on your best friend&amp;rsquo;s facebook timeline,
well you creepy fuck, you write it on your personal blog.
Umm, how should I begin ?
Let it be a question and answer round. Kind of like the rapid fire one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;1.) When did Pandey become your friend ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Oh that is easy, well let us see, &lt;em&gt;oh fuck you don&amp;rsquo;t remember do you&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
Wait I do - It was way back in class 6th I guess.
Pandey was in section &lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;, and she became friend with Rythm, my then crush.
Pandey wasn&amp;rsquo;t a direct friend, she became my friend through Rythm.&lt;br /&gt;
We used to tell Pandey about our tales of mischief, and our common friend Siddhant.
So yeah, I would say, class 6th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2.) When did you guys come close ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Why the fuck are you interested in my personal life so much. I mean how does it
matters to you.
&lt;em&gt;Boy you don&amp;rsquo;t ask the questions around here, I do&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Okay, this would be class 8th, Rhythm had left the school.&lt;br /&gt;
But I had this attachment to Pandey, it was some pleasure she gave me, she still does.&lt;br /&gt;
She is undoubtedly cute, you always want to keep one cute friend just in case you&amp;rsquo;re
single, dying alone at 40, you can marry her then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;3.) Why did you never propose Pandey, if you had a crush on her ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Okay so you will go all personal on me then, here you go.
I obviously had a crush on Pandey, I mean don&amp;rsquo;t get to see such beauty around,
I never could approach her initially due to Rhythm, well she was my first love.
And to be honest, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sort of those &amp;lsquo;rangbaaz&amp;rsquo; kids out there.
I was the one with oil on his head, pants quite up his waist, and more like a nerd you can say.
I don&amp;rsquo;t deny being a nerd, and nor has it let me to a downfall, but it does loses you some opportunities. (gains you some as well.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;4.) When did you realize you can never ask her out now ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
It can be called class 10th I suppose. I mean we were so close to be called a relationship
by everyone else, but we knew we were &amp;lsquo;only friends&amp;rsquo;, and it was perfect, I could not even dare
to lose such a beautiful relationship. And even I was &amp;lsquo;lite&amp;rsquo; by then, Pandey was someone who understood me like no other, I was the Prefect of Su-ur house by then (I still wonder why don&amp;rsquo;t they call the houses by their color name - simple &lt;strong&gt;Red House&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;br /&gt;
Pandey did a lot of work for Su-ur house, and hence we came close, we came close like no other.
And then I had a crush on Surabhi (again all that nerdiness stopped me), and Pandey knew about it, that strengthened our bond like no other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;5.) All that is cool, do you still love her ? Like do you want her as your girlfriend ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I would say &lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt; to this.
I mean a guy would be more than lucky to have Pandey by his side, I just know her too well, to be in a relationship with her.
A relationship is more like a puzzle you solve, layer by layer, by showering your love and gaining trust.
Pandey already has my utmost trust and I have hers. Also, now I don&amp;rsquo;t sexually feel about Pandey.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;But I have seen you looking at her breasts sometimes.. tsk. tsk.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Will you please shut the fuck up, it was long long ago, and I am a guy, every guy does this.&lt;br /&gt;
And well, she has a beauty, why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t someone not want to admire her. You just have a very vague and rude way of saying things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6.) Where do you see all of this heading ?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
If I have to keep a friend like Pandey, I would keep her till eternity.
You don&amp;rsquo;t get such friends in real life. Sometimes I do think if Pandey is just my hallicunation.
Well when others confirm that hallicunation it becomes a reality, and Pandey is that amazing reality which happened to me.&lt;br /&gt;
She has been with me through all my ups and downs, she has given me space when I was in a relationship, she has been throughout with me when I broke up, she was there with me when I got into BITS.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;And here she is with me, right in the messenger box, waiting for my reply, thinking I am working with some senior, and here I am, a fool, writing all this and making her wait&lt;/strong&gt;
It is me who could write books about her, entire memoirs, maybe a day will come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post will be deleted at 20th July 00:00&lt;/em&gt;
I will have a archive though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;signing off&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Avp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer 2017</title>
      <link>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/post/summer2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jul 2017 20:41:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aviral19.github.io/blog/post/summer2017/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So the summer is about to end, and a new session about to begin.&lt;br /&gt;
With new students coming in, you feel a bit older, a bit senior, a bit more
responsible. During school days summer was a time to have fun, enjoy yourself,
go out and have fun, while in college it becomes a time to work on your interests,
to learn and develop new skills, and return back to college as a better person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;here-a-few-things-i-began-during-my-summer-break-in-the-sequence:a2929c3358c09dc8bd5f5d61f5e96e3e&#34;&gt;Here a few things I began during my summer break in the sequence :&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Task finished will be striked off)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Began the summer working on QSTP on image search using Deep learning taught by &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sethuiyer&#34;&gt;Sethu Iyer&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Learning some static website generator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Hugo&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Learn Markdown&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python programming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Basics&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://classroom.udacity.com/courses/ud036&#34;&gt;Programming foundations in python - Udacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/del&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Python for Data Science&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Jupyter notebooks&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;pandas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;numpy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scikit-learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;matplotlib&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;nltk&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/home&#34;&gt;Machine Learning course by Andrew Ng&lt;/a&gt;
*&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;books-i-read:a2929c3358c09dc8bd5f5d61f5e96e3e&#34;&gt;Books I read :&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did finish all of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25855506-adulthood-is-a-myth&#34;&gt;Adulthood Is a Myth (Sarah&amp;rsquo;s Scribbles #1)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25614898-when-breath-becomes-air&#34;&gt;When Breath Becomes Air by Paul Kalanithi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/25744928-deep-work&#34;&gt;Deep Work: Rules for Focused Success in a Distracted World
by Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/28862.The_Prince&#34;&gt;The Prince by Niccolò Machiavelli&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/3.Harry_Potter_and_the_Sorcerer_s_Stone&#34;&gt;Harry Potter and the Sorcerer&amp;rsquo;s Stone (Harry Potter #1) by JK Rowling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am pretty happy with my performance in book reading.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my summer in a giffy. I plan to finish the remaining items before September 1, 2017.
I also plan to write entire life goals, will update the link here.&lt;br /&gt;
Also I will keep on writing posts like these every 2 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;signing off&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Avp&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>